<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thompson&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thompson&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:28:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Addictiveness of Competitive Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2-addiction-and-competitive-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:28:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2-addiction-and-competitive-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ranked-based-matchmaking&#34;&gt;Ranked Based Matchmaking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranked based matchmaking is a system that matches players of similar skill levels together based on a player&amp;rsquo;s rank, defined by their performance in matches, ideally creating an competitive environment where players feel challenged but not overwhelmed. This system is used in many competitive games: Valorant, League of Legends, Overwatch, and Counter-Strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of these ranking algorithms is to take all the data points from the game such as match outcome, round differencial, individual performance and create a score that represents the player&amp;rsquo;s skill level. Whilst these algorithms are usually kept secret to prevent exploitation, they are developed by multi-million dollar corporations which are incentivized to keep players hooked to the game. Therefore, they have a strong incentive to make sure that each game is optimized to have a 50-50 probability for win or lose, creating a sense of competitiveness and challenge for the player.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upbringing and Mindset: Privileged and Underprivileged</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/1-upbringing-and-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:49:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/1-upbringing-and-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;upbringing&#34;&gt;Upbringing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upbringing: the treatment and instruction received by a child from its parents throughout its childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a privileged, international childhood and meeting many people from similar backgrounds, I have always had many safety nets growing up. My family and families that I was in contact with I did not have the financial stress that 23% of UK families and carers have (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.childrenssociety.org.uk/sites/default/files/2023-11/feeling-the-strain.pdf&#34;&gt;Feeling the Strain - The Children&amp;rsquo;s Society&lt;/a&gt;). Now that I am in university, by working a part-time job and escaping the &amp;lsquo;bubble&amp;rsquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ve been inside of, I would like to reflect on how upbringing and mindset effects long-term life trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
